Thomas P. Curran

3332 Kimberly Way, San Mateo, CA 94403 +1 508.212.9212

TP.Curran89@gmail.com Github: TCurran4589

Research Interests

I am interested in the applications of machine learning and artificial intelligence in complex systems. I am particularly interested in using reinforcement learning algorithms in intelligent learning environments to personalize student learning experiences and assist teachers with socio-emotional learning. Additionally, I am interested in using artificial intelligence algorithms in educational video games and other interactive media.

Education

University of Chicago

2016 - 2018

- Master of Public Policy (MPP)
- Graduate Certificate in Computational Social Science
 - <u>Capstone Paper</u>: Using Neural Networks and Support Vector Machines to Predict School Performance in Oklahoma
- Graduate Certificate in Survey Research Methods

Stonehill College 2007 - 2011

- Bachelor of Arts, English Language, and Literature

Professional Positions

Data Scientist 2018 - Present

Chan Zuckerberg Initiative: Education Initiative

 Conduct rigorous research and program evaluation of the Summit Learning platform's products and services to assess the impact on student and teacher outcomes.

Data Scientist 2015 - 2018

Oklahoma Public School Resource Center (OPSRC)

 Collected, managed, and analyzed data to support OPSRC's mission of improving education through policy throughout Oklahoma, especially concerning school funding policies.

Research Positions

2017 - 2018 **Graduate Research Assistant** NORC Center of Excellence in Survey Research Graduate Research Assistant for Dr. Rupa Datta, assisting her as Principal Investigator for the National Survey for Early Care and Education. Summer Intern 2017 **NORC** Assisted Principal Investigator with developing a sample frame for surveys assessing the accessibility of child care facilities in rural communities. Wrote web scrapers to collect, clean, and manage unstructured data. **Teaching Positions Teaching Assistant, Crime Prevention** 2018 Prof. Jens Ludwig, University of Chicago Held weekly office hours and review sessions on class materials for students. Graded papers, homework, and assessments. Tutor 2017 - 2018 R Bar Held weekly workshops for teaching R to graduate students. Developed teaching materials in parallel with core MPP curriculum to support graduate students implementing class content using R. 8th Grade Science 2013 - 2015 Roosevelt Middle School, Oklahoma City Public Schools (OKCPS) Developed an assessment tracking tool to improve teaching and target specific content for appropriate scaffolding. Represented eighth-grade science on OKCPS Curriculum Transition committee from old state standards to new Next Generation Science Standards. Selected by the State Department of Education for OK-SCI Leadership class.

Corps Member

Teach For America

2013 - 2015

Professional Membership(s)

- International Educational Data Mining Society
- The International Artificial Intelligence in Education Society (IAIED)
- Americorps Alumni
- Teach For America Alumni

Fellowships & Awards

- Segal Education Service Award, 2015
- Segal Education Service Award, 2014
- Leadership for Educational Equity Summer Policy & Advocacy Fellowship. 2014

Additional Training and Coursework

Oregon State University

2020

2018

- Computer Science Coursework: Introduction to Computer Science I (CS161), Introduction to Computer Science II (CS162)
- Mathematics: Differential Calculus (MTH251), Elements of Discrete Mathematics (MTH231

Becker Friedman Institute for Economics Open Source Macroeconomics Laboratory Bootcamp

- Underwent training in advanced mathematics and economics theory to conduct public policy and economic analysis using open-source computational tools and frameworks.

Additional Positions Held

Marketing Coordinator

2012 - 2013

Cartera Commerce, Inc.

- Managed and analyzed marketing databases for developing the content strategy across products and assisted in lead generation strategies.

Member Services Representative

2011 - 2012

Cartera Commerce. Inc.

- Managed customer relationships and resolved customer-facing technical issues to improve the product experience for customers.

References

Gian Gonzaga

Data Science Director, Education Chan Zuckerberg Initiative GGonzaga@ChanZuckerberg.com

James Saxon

Fellow, Center for Spatial Data Science University of Chicago JSaxon@Uchicago.edu

David Porcaro

Director of Learning Engineering Chan Zuckerberg Initiative David.Porcarco@Chanzuckerberg.com